speedcafe.com 2019-08-21

# Speedcafe Pty Ltd Privacy Policy |

### How to contact us

Speedcafe Pty Ltd is committed to working with our readers to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about privacy.

To contact us with a compliment or complaint or a privacy question, you can:

  * Write to us  
Speedcafe Pty Ltd  
PO Box 945  
Paradise Point 4216 ; OR
  * Call our office on (07) 5580 3985 between the office hours of 9.00am and 5.00pm Monday to Friday.

### Your acknowledgement of our Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is published on our website in order to meet our obligation under National Privacy Principle 5.1 which requires us to set out our policies on the management of personal information in a clearly expressed document which is available to anyone who asks for it.

Without limiting the generality of the above statement, your use of this website constitutes an acknowledgement that you have been made aware of our privacy policies.

This policy does not create or confer upon any individual any rights, or impose upon Speedcafe Pty Ltd any rights or obligations outside of, or in addition to, those rights or obligations imposed by the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), the Spam Act 2003 (Cth) or related legislation (‘the legislation’). Should there be, in specific case any inconsistency between this statement and the Act, this statement shall be interpreted, in respect of that case, to give effect to, and comply with the legislation.

### Personal Information

Personal Information means information we hold about you from which your identity is either apparent or can be reasonably determined.

### Uses and Sharing

We use personal information you provide only for the purposes consistent with the reason you provided it, or for a directly related purpose.

Generally, we will not use your personal information to communicate or market to you unless we have either your implied or express consent but in situations where it is impractical to obtain your prior consent, we will ensure you have the ability to opt out of future such communications.

We do not share your personal information with other organisations unless you give us your express consent, or where sharing is otherwise required or permitted by law, or where this is necessary on a temporary basis to enable our contractors to perform specific functions.

### Your rights and choices

You may interact with us anonymously where this is lawful and practicable.

You have the right to request access to personal information. This right is subject to certain exceptions allowed by law.

You may instruct us to remove any previous consent you provided to receive news, information and marketing communications.

### About this Privacy Policy

We respect your personal information and your right to privacy.

At Speedcafe Pty Ltd, protecting your privacy when handling your personal information is very important to us and is fundamental to the way we serve you.

At Speedcaft Pty Ltd we know that when you give us your personal information, it imposes a serious responsibility upon us. We are committed to protecting your personal information and maintaining your trust.

This Privacy Policy describes the information that may be collected by Speedcafe Pty Ltd, the choices you can make about your personal information and how we protect your personal information.

### Why we collect personal information and how we may use it

Generally, Speedcafe Pty Ltd will collect personal information directly from you, and only to the extent necessary to provide a Speedcafe Pty Ltd product or service, including our agency functions, or to carry out our internal administrative operations. An agency function means a service that we provide to you on behalf of another organisation, such as our POSTbillpay and [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) services.

We may collect personal information from you when;

  * register your details on either Speedcafe.com or Speedcafe.co.nz.
  * enter a competition on Speedcafe.com or Speedcafe.co.nz
  * verbally provide details and information for any promotion for Speedcafe.com or Speedcafe.co.nz
  * register on the Speedcafe.com Classifieds
  * participate in any survey or questionnaire on Speedcafe.com or Speedcafe.co.nz.

We will collect personal information from you by lawful and fair means and not in an unreasonably intrusive way.

We will use your personal information only for the particular purpose that you provided it, or for a directly related purpose. We may otherwise use your personal information where that other use is:

  * required or permitted by law; or
  * with your express or implied consent.

### Direct marketing and your privacy

From time to time we may use the personal information we collect from you to identify particular Speedcafe Pty Ltd products and services which we believe may be of interest to you. We may then contact you to let you know about these products and services and how they may benefit you. We will always give you a choice to opt put of receiving such information in future.

### Electronic marketing

Where we use your personal information to send you marketing information by e-mail, SMS, MMS or other electronic means we may do so with your express or implied consent. Consent may be implied from our existing business relationship or where you have directly or indirectly provided us with your electronic address.

All of our electronic marketing activities will comply with the requirements of the Spam Act 2003 (Cth).

### Information sharing

We have a strict duty to maintain the privacy of all personal information we hold about you. However, certain exceptions do apply. For example, where disclosure of your personal information is:

  * **authorised or required by law**  
e.g. disclosure to various government departments and agencies such as the Australian Taxation Office, CentreLink, Child Support Agency, or disclosure to courts under subpoena.
  * **in the public interest**  
e.g. where a crime, fraud or misdemeanour is committed or suspected, and disclosure against the customer’s rights to confidentiality is justified.
  * **with your consent**  
Your consent may be implied or express and it may also be verbal or written.

### Updating your information

It is inevitable that some personal information which we hold will become out of date. We will take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information which we hold remains accurate and, if you advise us of a change of details, we will amend our records accordingly.

### Access to your personal information

Speedcafe Pty Ltd will, upon your request, and subject to applicable privacy laws, provide you with access to your personal information that is held by us. However, we ask that you identify, as clearly as possible, the type/s of information requested.

Speedcafe Pty Ltd will deal with your request to provide access to your personal information in a reasonable time – usually within 30 days of receipt of your request.

### Exceptions

Your right to access your personal information is not absolute. In certain circumstances, the law permits us to refuse your request to provide you with access to your personal information, such as circumstances where:

  * access would pose a serious threat to the life or health of any individual;
  * access would have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of others;
  * the request is frivolous or vexatious;
  * the information relates to a commercially sensitive decision making process;
  * access would be unlawful; or
  * access may prejudice enforcement activities, a security function or commercial negotiations.

### Freedom of Information laws

In addition to privacy laws, you may have rights to access your personal information contained in certain Speedcafe Pty Ltd documents. Details on how to apply for access to these documents are contained in the Freedom of Information Act 1982 (FOI Act).  
More information is available at freedom of information.

### Information collected on this website

We may collect non-personal information from you such as browser type, operating system, and web pages visited to help us manage our web site.  
We use cookies and other internet technologies to manage our website and certain online products and services. We do not use these technologies to collect or store personal information unless you have opted in to such a feature.  
Our internet server logs the following information which is provided by your browser for statistical purposes only:

  * the type of browser and operating system you are using
  * your Internet Service Provider and top level domain name (for example – .com, .gov, .au, .uk etc)
  * the address of any referring web site (for example – the previous web site you visited), and
  * your computer’s IP (Internet Protocol) address (a number which is unique to the machine through which you are connected to the internet).

All of this information is used by Speedcafe Pty Ltd for aggregated statistical analyses or systems administration purposes only. No attempt will be made to identify users or their browsing activities, except where required by or under law.

### Links to other sites

The Speedcafe Pty Ltd site contains links to other sites. We are ultimately not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. We encourage you to read and understand the privacy policies on those websites prior to providing any information to them.

Some of the content appearing on the Speedcafe Pty Ltd website may be supplied by third parties, for example, by framing third party web sites or the incorporation through “framesets” of content supplied by third party application service providers. In such cases Speedcafe Pty Ltd will ensure that our contractual arrangements with these third parties protect your personal information in compliance with privacy laws.  

### Website comments policy

The Speedcafe Pty Ltd site contains comments submitted by website users.  Comments are automatically published by DISQUS. Speedcafe.com goes to every effort to ensure inappropriate comments are removed immediately. We encourage users to flag/report comments which should be removed from public viewing.

As a DISQUS comments user, you are obligated by DISQUS to abide by the basic rules as per the following:

  * Targeted harassment and encouraging others to do so
  * Spam
  * Impersonation
  * Direct threat of harm
  * Posting personally identifiable information
  * Inappropriate profile content

The following actions are also not permitted:

  * One word comments
  * The use of multiple accounts
  * Comments that are not relevant to the news story
  * Usernames which may be offensive and/or contain an excessive amount of emojis
  * Regular posting of the same comment

Speedcafe.com reserves the right to ban or suspend a user from publishing a comment on Speedcafe.com at any time. Any decision made by the Speedcafe.com comments administrator is final.

For more information on what and how DISQUS stores your data, please visit: <https://disqus.com/support>

### Searches

Search terms that you enter when using our search engine are collected, but are not associated with any other information that we collect. We use these search terms for the purpose of aggregated statistical analyses so we can ascertain what people are looking for on our website, and to improve the services that we provide.

Also, from time to time, we may use external companies to provide us with detailed aggregate statistical analyses of our website traffic. At no time is any personal information made available to these companies, nor is the aggregate information ever merged with personal information such as your name, address, email address or other information you would consider sensitive or would compromise your privacy.

### Website security and privacy

We understand that you may be concerned about the security of the personal information we collect from you online.

Accordingly, we have systems in place to ensure our online dealings with you are as secure as your dealings with us in person, or on the telephone.

In those instances where we secure your personal information in transit to us and upon receipt, we use the industry standard encryption software, Secured Socket Layer (SSL) 128 bit encryption. Your browser may also display a lock symbol on its bottom task bar line to indicate this secure transmission is in place.

For site security purposes and to ensure this service remains available to all users, we employ software programs to monitor network traffic in order to identify unauthorised attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause us damage. Except for authorised law enforcement investigations, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits other than those uses identified in this policy. Unauthorised modification or misuse of information stored in this system will be investigated and may result in criminal prosecution.

### Information transfer

If Speedcafe Pty Ltd transfers personal information to countries outside Australia, we will only do so in compliance with all applicable Australian data protection and privacy laws.

Speedcafe Pty Ltd will take reasonable steps to protect personal information no matter what country it is stored in or transferred to. We have procedures and data transfer contracts as appropriate to help ensure this.

### Further information on privacy

You can obtain further general information about your privacy rights and privacy law from the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner by:

  * calling their Privacy Hotline on 1300 363 992, or
  * visiting their web site at www.privacy.gov.au (External link) , or
  * by writing to:  
The Australian Information Commissioner

**Last Updated:**  17 August 2018
